C: 805-550-8231 | ryan.stuhl@gmail.com | ryanstuhl.com

I am applying for a position with your company because I feel that we both possess something to benefit each other. I possess the ability to develop pixel perfect front-end experiences which work on an array of devices. I also have the ability to make smart decisions when it comes to how people interact with those pixel perfect designs. Included in my toolbox of abilities, a Bachelor of Science degree, seven years experience building web sites and a few past experiences working within unique teams of developers.

What do you possess? Evolution. A team of like-minded people who enjoy what they do and are able to learn from one another to help broaden their experiences and their personal abilities; a fertile ecosystem of people bringing different and unique skills to the discussions. I believe working as part of a team helps an individual grow and develop new skills and discover new opportunities.

Three things I have been passionate about include web development and design, user interactions resulting in positive experiences, and cutting edge new technologies. All three of these traits are in the title of my Bachelor of Science major; Web Design & Interactive Media.

These are exciting times to be in the digital and new media space. With the right people and the right attitudes, nothing is unachievable. I have the skills and the drive to become a great asset in your organization. I look forward to the opportunity to be part of something incredible.

"We know what we are, but know not what we may be." – William Shakespeare

RYAN **STUHL**

1277 Belridge Street 9B, Oceano, CA 93445 | C: 805-550-8231 | ryan.stuhl@gmail.com

Career Overview

Since graduating from the Art Institute of California - Hollywood, I have had experience working with a variety of different companies and agencies in the San Luis Obispo area. I have interned at two local shops where I had the opportunity to integrate with two unique team structures. During my final year of pursuing my Bachelor of Science degree I started employment full time as a front end web developer. In the time I have been employed at this agency I have increased my skill level to include back end development as well as user experience and user interface design.

Qualifications

- Seven years experience with Adobe Creative Suite
- Bachelor of Science Degree in Web Design & Interactive Media
- Four years experience in User Experience and User Interface design
- Six years experience in front end development
- Three years experience in back end development
- Three years experience with MVC frameworks

- Three years experience with subversion
- Three years experience creating wireframes for various types of projects
- One year experience with SSH connectivity and server maintenance
- Web content management
- Landing page development
- Customizing Wordpress themes

Technical Skills

<u>Skills</u>	<u>Experience</u>	<u>Total Years</u>	<u>Last Used</u>
HTML5/CSS3	Proficient	7	2015
JQuery/Javascript	Advanced Novice	3	2015
UX/UI Design	Intermediate	3	2015
PHP	Intermediate Novice	3	2015
Laravel 3	Intermediate	2	2014
Laravel 4	Intermediate	2	2015
Angular.js	Novice	1mo	2015
Twitter Bootstrap	Intermediate	2.5	2015
Foundation 4	Intermediate	1.5	2014
Adobe Photoshop	Expert	7	2015
Adobe InDesign	Expert	5	2013
Omnigraffle	Expert	2	2015
Written Communication	Proficient	10+	2015
Verbal Communication	Proficient	10+	2015

Accomplishments

Landing Page Development

 For the past three years I have helped in creating landing pages for celebrity eBay auctions. The structured landing pages I helped create have reduced development times from four days to a few hours. With the addition of jQuery and various libraries, I have assisted in creating desired experiences sought after by the clients

Team Management

For the past three years I have assisted in creating working with a variety of sizes
of teams ranging from Internal Project Management to Development Team
Scrums.

Programming

Upon my completion of my pursuit of a Bachelor of Science degree I have been
programming for personal clients on a freelance basis and for agency clients as
both an intern and as a full time employee. In the past five years I have expanded
my programming talents from a simple front end developer to a full stack developer with a working understanding of advanced programming languages.

IT Solutions

For two and a half years I have been responsible for the IT solutions in my office.
This includes troubleshooting and fixing network connections and phone systems, setting up computers for new hires, recycling computers from past employees, and setting up and managing accounts for various software and services utilized by teams within the company

Work Experience

Web Developer Cause Media Group

06/2011 - Current San Luis Obispo, CA

I am currently working at StudioGood, a division of Cause Media Group as a full stack developer. I started at Cause Media Group under another division, Kompolt Online Auction Agency where I was responsible for building eBay landing and listing pages for celebrity aligned charities such as Bright Pink, GRAMMY Foundation, MusiCares, MuttNation, ATAS, and GLIDE Foundation. I still create these landing and listing pages but my role has expanded to include support for the various clients at the StudioGood division as well. This has been integral in my own personal development as a full stack developer as I have been given the opportunity to work on larger projects within a team and gained exposure to back end programming. I also feel I have learned a great deal about time management and prioritization.

Intern to Design Team Shopatron

09/2010 - 04/2011 San Luis Obispo, CA

I was hired as an intern to the design team at Shopatron where I worked on various eCommerce stores for a number of clients including but not limited to National Geographic Bags, Gitzo Lights, and Can-AM/BRP. I have numerous endorsements and recommendations readily available upon request.

Work Experience (cont.)

Development Intern Hathway Tech 04/2010 - 06/2010 San Luis Obispo, CA At Hathway Tech I was an intern to the development team helping to customize and update Joomla websites. This was my first real world experience with a CMS. I helped create pages for the SLO Rattlers Baseball Team and the San Luis Obispo Business Center.

Education and Training

Bachelor of Science

Web Design & Interactive Media
The Art Institute of California – Hollywood

From February 2008 until December 2011 I pursued my Bachelor of Science degree at the Art Institute of California – Hollywood. In the time I was attending college I was president of the Web Development Club and worked part time as a mentor to other students in my field of study. My GPA was a 3.8 and I was a repeat student on the Dean's List as well as the President's List

G.E.D

Provincial Government of Alberta

In January of 2008 I challenged and received my G.E.D before applying for a student visa to attend the Art Institute of California.